PRATIK VAISHNAVI

pvaishnavi@cs.stonybrook.edu | Stony Brook, NY
pratik18v.github.io | linkedin.com/in/pratik-vaishnavi-aa2585b3

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

8+ years of research experience in Machine Learning, Deep Learning and Computer Vision, covering the following **topics**: adversarial robustness, transfer learning, knowledge distillation, self-supervised learning, domain generalization, and video understanding; and the following **models**: classifiers, detectors, generative AI models, transformers, and segmentation models.

EDUCATION

PhD, Computer Science, Stony Brook University

08/2018 - 05/2024 (Expected)

Thesis: Improving the Usability of Methods for Training and Evaluating Secure ML Models

Topics: Adversarial Machine Learning, Knowledge Transfer, Foundation Models, LLM Pre-training

MS, Computer Science, Stony Brook University

08/2016 - 05/2018

Thesis: Generating Temporal Action Proposals in Long Untrimmed Videos

Topics: Video Understanding, Action Detection, Sequential Modelling (LSTMs, GRUs)

BTech, Electronics, Sardar Vallabhbhai National Institute of Technology

07/2012 - 05/2016

Thesis: Developing Software for Drone-Based Precision Farming

EXPERIENCE

Sony Al, Security & Privacy Research Intern, Tokyo, Japan

05/2023 - 09/2023

Developed an efficient method to train secure object detectors (Faster-RCNN, YOLO, SSD) using dataset distillation. Reduced training time by 50% while preserving performance and robustness, in turn reducing monetary costs and environmental impact associated with GPU usage.

Amazon, Applied Scientist Intern, Seattle, WA

06/2021 - 09/2021

Developed a video-based camera obstruction detector using 3D-CNNs to improve the reliability of Amazon One devices in unrestricted deployment settings. Curated a camera obstruction dataset from scratch, containing over 3000 videos collected using 19 unique obstructions. Work was published at Amazon Machine Learning Conference and spawned a dedicated project for a new full-time employee.

Amazon, Applied Scientist Intern, Remote

05/2020 - 08/2020

Developed a novel spoof image generation method using Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs). Used this data to reduce the ACER of the spoof detector for the Amazon One device by 14% on average across 13 unseen spoof categories. Work was published at Amazon Computer Vision Conference.

SKILLS

- Coding | Python (NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, OpenCV), Bash, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- **Deep Learning** | PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras
- **Documentation** | LaTeX, Markdown
- Miscellaneous | Linux, MATLAB, Git, AWS, Docker

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- Accelerating Certified Robustness Training via Knowledge Transfer
 NeurIPS 2022 | P. Vaishnavi, K. Eykholt, and A. Rahmati
- On the Feasibility of Compressing Certifiably Robust Neural Networks
 TSRML Workshop @ NeurIPS 2022 | P. Vaishnavi, V. Krish, F. Ahmed, K. Eykholt, and A. Rahmati
- <u>Transferring Adversarial Robustness Through Robust Representation Matching</u>
 <u>USENIX Security Symposium 2022 | P. Vaishnavi, K. Eykholt, and A. Rahmati</u>
- Ares: A System-Oriented Wargame Framework for Adversarial ML
 IEEE Security and Privacy Workshops 2022 | F. Ahmed, <u>P. Vaishnavi</u>, K. Eykholt, and A. Rahmati
- <u>Can Attention Masks Improve Adversarial Robustness?</u>
 <u>EDSMLS Workshop @ AAAI 2020 | P. Vaishnavi,</u> T. Cong, K. Eykholt, A. Prakash, and A. Rahmati
 Complete List on Google Scholar

OTHER PROJECTS

- Multi-layer Neural Composer for Personalized Product Descriptions (Fall 2017 and Spring 2018)
 Investigated attention-based sequence-to-sequence language generation methods as a scalable approach for delivering personalized e-commerce product descriptions. Specifically, developed a multimodal learning method to refine product embeddings by collectively using image and text data.
- Large-scale Video Understanding (Spring 2017)
 Developed a classifier to assign video-level labels for the YouTube-8M dataset containing 8 million videos. Used a combination of pre-trained feature encoders and Mixture of Experts to improve the average Precision@k by 7% over the available baseline.

REVIEWER DUTIES

- Conferences: CVPR, ICCV, ECCV, ACCV, NeurIPS, ICLR, ICML, USENIX Security, IEEE S&P
- Journals: IEEE Transactions on Image Proc., IEEE Transactions on Info. Forensics & Security
- Workshops: TSRML @ NeurIPS 2022, EDSMLS @ AAAI 2020

TEACHING ASSISTANTSHIPS (STONY BROOK UNIVERSITY)

- CSE 508: Network Security (Fall 2019 & Spring 2021)
- CSE 527: Introduction to Computer Vision (Spring 2019)
- CSE 512: Machine Learning (Fall 2018)

AWARDS AND EXTRACURICULARS

- Best Poster Award Recipient, Graduate Research Day, 2023
- Organizer, Adversarial Machine Learning Reading Group, 2022
- Invited Speaker, IBM Security Group Seminar, 2021
- Mentor, Women in Science and Engineering Lab Rotations, 2021
- Organizing Committee, Graduate Research Day, 2021
- Vice President, Computer Science Graduate Student Organization, 2020-2021
- Editor, College Newsletter, 2015
- Executive Board Member, Literary Affairs Committee, 2013-2015